# **BEN FOK**

Leavenworth, WA. | Phone: (530)314-1419 | Email: benfok8@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/benfok | GitHub Profile: github.com/benfok | Portfolio site: benfok.github.io/portfolio1

# **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer blending technical skills with over a decade of operational, people and senior leadership experience as an elite level educator and director at a Fortune 1000 company. Ben is uniquely positioned as a creative engineer who understands the role and the strategic impact of technology across all facets of the business, and one who can speak both the language of the web and that of your team to drive results.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, SQL, Node.js, Express, ReactJS, jQuery, RESTful APIs, Handlebars.js, Bootstrap, MongoDB

Applications: Microsoft 365 and Full Office Suite, Adobe Workfront, Articulate 360, Success Factors

## **EXPERIENCE**

CEO | TIDY LINES LLC November 2021 – Present | Leavenworth, WA

- o Freelance web development, copy writing, project management and consulting.
- Currently contracted by Vail Resorts; a Fortune 1000 company. Project, content and contractor management across 34 websites.
- Improved workflow efficiency and reduced issue resolution time by over 30% within two months.
- Project Lead for digital content execution for product launch in Match '22 and content migration for 3 new acquisitions beginning June '22.

Director of Skier Services | Stevens Pass, Vail Resorts October 2013 - November 2021 | Leavenworth, WA

- o Director of 7 departments totaling 400+ employees and over \$4M in direct revenue. Doubled revenue in a 5-year period.
- o Project manager and SME on development of an industry leading custom ecommerce platform handing \$6M+ annual revenue.
- Created and deployed a critical thinking model companywide (40K employees) to improve decision making and reduce incidents by up to 75%.
- o Designed and executed training for all resort staff (800+) and management staff annually.
- o Recognized nationally for my leadership skills and business impact. [National Ski Areas Association, SNOW Operating, Vail Resorts]

# **PROJECTS**

#### THE HAPPY PLACE

An alternative to social media. A site intentionally without images, "likes", comments or friend counters where users are simply encouraged to journal on daily gratitudes as a positive habit known to promote mental wellbeing. Posts can be made public or private.

My Role: All Javascript for backend webserver, MySQL data interaction and front end scripts. Added CSS for modals and responsive design.

Technologies Used: JavaScript, Node.js, MySQL, CSS, HTML, Express.js, Sequelize, Handlebars.js, Restful APIs

Repository: github.com/benfok/The-Happy-Place Deployed at: the-happy-place-app.herokuapp.com/

## **PUBCRAWLER**

A fun inspired application where a user can enter their city, town or neighborhood and select from a list of the closest drinking locations in any order. The app will then calculate and map out the optimal walking route. The perfect app for planning your next (responsible) pub crawl.

My Role: All Javascript for front end, 3rd party API integration and mapping component, use of local browser storage to save and render data

Technologies Used: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, API interfacing Repository: <a href="mailto:github.com/benfok/pub-crawler">github.com/benfok/pub-crawler</a> Deployed at: <a href="mailto:benfok.github.io/pub-crawler">benfok.github.io/pub-crawler</a>

#### **CODE QUIZ**

A timed quiz app serving randomly generated questions and storing high scores in the browser.

My Role: Sole developer Technologies Used: Javascript, CSS, HTML Repository: github.com/benfok/code-quiz Deployed at: benfok.github.io/code-quiz/

#### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development Certificate | University of Washington – 2022

JavaScript, Asynchronous JavaScript and Node.js | Codecademy.com

Business, Physics and Statistics | Chepstow Comprehensive, Wales U.K – 1997-2003

enepsion comprehensive, video on 1557 2005

TEFL Certified | Full Certified Ski Instructor and former Regional Technical Team Member | Vail Resorts Camp II Graduate